Guide to the AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council records
1880-2010
circa 1945-1995
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
0450
AFL-CIO.$bWashington State Labor Council
approximately 208 cubic feet
Records of a labor organization that functions as the political and legislative arm of the AFL-CIO in Washington
The Washington State Labor Council (WSLC) was formed in 1957 by a merger of the Washington State Federation of Labor and the Washington State CIO Council. These two labor bodies had been bitter rivals in the 1930s but had slowly grown closer together. The need to cooperate to defeat right-to-work measures (Initiative 198 in 1956 and Initiative 202 in 1958) cemented their alliance. After defeating these measures, labor groups took the offensive. The United Labor Lobby (ULL), which grew out of the committees created to defeat the right-to-work initiatives, won an extension of the 40 hour maximum work week to all Washington workers and an expansion of the unemployment insurance system in 1959. The ULL and WSLC were not able to follow up on these victories in the early 1960s as the increasingly Republican state legislature soon forced labor back on the defensive.
When Evan (Ed) Weston retired as WSLC president in 1961, Joe Davis was elected president. Davis beefed up the Council’s voter registration and get-out-the-vote drives. In 1966 Davis launched a major new effort, dubbed Project ‘66, to increase labor’s influence and broaden its political agenda. Project ‘66 increased the amount of money that member unions paid to the Council and doubled the Council’s staff. These changes allowed the Council to monitor government agencies more closely and to lobby on new subjects of legislative interest, such as tax reform and consumer protection. The new program did score a few notable victories. The WSLC increased its influence in the Washington Department of Labor and Industries. The Council also won limited collective bargaining rights for public employees in 1967, broadened the workers’ compensation program to include essentially all workers in 1971, provided assistance to efforts to pass civil rights laws in the 1960s, and was instrumental in obtaining several consumer protection laws in the 1970s. Project ‘66 thus increased the number of issues on which the Council had legislative influence and built greater cooperation between labor, civil rights, and consumer protection groups. Nonetheless, the WSLC did not substantially increase its ability to elect labor-friendly candidates to the legislature. As such, labor remained vulnerable to lobbying assaults from employer groups throughout the 1970s and 1980s, suffering occasional defeats in struggles over the workers’ compensation and unemployment programs.
The following people served as officers and staff (WSLC): Evan (Ed) Weston, president, 1957-1961; Joe Davis, president, 1962-1980; Marvin Williams, secretary-treasurer, 1959-1980, president, 1985-1993; Lawrence Kenney, research director, 1969-1980, secretary-treasurer, 1980-1985, president, 1985-1993; Louis O. Stewart, education director, 1967-1982.
Organized into 16 accessions.
Accession No. 0450-001, AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council records, 1957-1962
Accession No. 0450-002, AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council ephemera, 1919-1962
Accession No. 0450-003, AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council records, 1935-1978
Accession No. 0450-005, AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council records, 1958-1981
Accession No. 0450-006, AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council records, 1946-1982
Accession No. 0450-007, AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council records, 1963-1983
Accession No. 0450-008, AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council records, 1938-1985
Accession No. 0450-009, AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council records, 1957-1985
Accession No. 0450-010, AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council records, 1957-1967
Accession No. 0450-011, AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council records, 1968-1984
Accession No. 0450-013, AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council records, 1940-1992
Accession No. 0450-015, AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council t-shirts and mug, 1990
Accession No. 0450-016, AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council records, 1989-2010
Accession No. 0450-017, AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council records, 1970-2000
Accession No. 0450-018, AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council tool collection, circa 1880-1930
Accession No. 0450-019, AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council Records, 1902-2004
Correspondence, minutes, administrative files, reports, subject files, audio tapes, videocassettes, ephemera, and artifacts. Includes records from the term of Joe Davis as president (1961-1979), with lesser amounts from the terms of his predecessor, Evan Weston, and his successor, Marvin L. Williams (1979-1986). Also includes records of Williams as secretary-treasurer, 1959-1979; together with records of Louis O. Stewart, education director, from 1967; Sam Kinville, government affairs director, 1967-1974; and Lawrence Kenney, research director, from 1969; and records relating to AFL-CIO Committee on Political Education (COPE), Federated American Insurance Company, Labor's League for Political Education, and United Labor Lobby. Also includes records reflecting activities of Washington State Labor Council officers and staff on governmental and private committees. Correspondents, other than unions, include Christenia Alden, Alexander E. Barkan, Andrew J. Biermiller, Daniel J. Evans, Arthur Gaetz, Thomas Groth, Henry M. Jackson, Warren G. Magnuson, George Meany, Thomas M. Pelly, Albert D. Rosellini, Elizabeth Schimling, Norman Schut, and Washington State Dept. of Labor and Industries.
Forms part of the Labor Archives of Washington
Open to all users, but access to portions of the papers restricted. Contact Special Collections for details.
Bender, Rick$vCorrespondence.; Davis, Joe$q(Joe H.); Kinville, Sam.; Stewart, Louis.; Weston, Evan M.; Williams, Marvin L.; AFL-CIO.$bWashington State Labor Council$vArchives.; AFL-CIO.$bCommittee on Political Education.; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Washington (State)$xLabor unions.; Washington (State)$xPolitics and government.; Labor$zWashington (State); Labor unions$xPolitical activity.; Labor unions$zWashington (State); Labor unions$xFinance.; Labor movement$zWashington (State); Workers' compensation$zWashington (State); Ephemera.; Business correspondence.; Minutes (Records); Sound recordings.; Audiotapes.; Correspondence.; Minutes.; Reports.
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor Unions; Labor History; Washington (State)
- AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council records, 1957-1962; 0450-001; 7.5 cubic feet 15 boxes
  Arranged in 4 series:
  Correspondence
  Financial records
  Other administrative records
  National Council on Crime and Delinquency, Washington Citizens Council records
  General correspondence, minutes, clippings, and related records. Includes a list of resolutions passed by the WASHINGTON STATE LABOR COUNCIL Executive Board from 1957 to 1961.
  Open to all users.
  Gift of AFL-CIO, Washington State Labor Council, March 17, 1964
  - CORRESPONDENCE, SERIES I (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Correspondence: Incoming, Subseries A
      - Agriculture Worker's Union, 1959; 1 item (Box-folder 1/1)
      - Alaska Fishermen's Union, 1958; 1 item (Box-folder ½)
      - Alaska State Federation of Labor, AFL-CIO, 1960; 1 item (Box-folder 1/3)
      - Allied Printing Trades Council, Seattle and vicinity, 1958-1959; 2 items (Box-folder 1/4)
      - Aluminum Trades Council, Wenatchee, 1961; 1 item (Box-folder 1/5)
      - American Civil Liberties Union, Washington, 1959; 2 items (Box-folder 1/6)
      - AFL-CIO, American Federationist, 1957-1958; 3 items (Box-folder 1/7)
      - AFL-CIO, Building and Construction Trades Council, 1959-1962; 6 items (Box-folder 1/8)
        - Bremerton and vicinity
          - Everett, 1960-1961; 2 items (Box-folder 1/9)
          - Grays Harbor, 1961; 3 items (Box-folder 1/10)
          - Northeastern, 1960; 1 item (Box-folder 1/11)
        - Washington-Northern Idaho
          - Oregon State, 1960; 1 item (Box-folder 1/12)
          - Olympia, 1960-1961; 5 items (Box-folder 1/13)
          - Port Angeles, 1959-1960; 3 items (Box-folder 1/14)
          - Sandusky, 1958; 1 item (Box-folder 1/15)
          - Seattle, 1958-1959; 2 items (Box-folder 1/16)
          - Skagit Valley, 1959; 1 item (Box-folder 1/17)
          - Spokane, 1957-1959; 2 items (Box-folder 1/18)
          - Wenatchee, 1959; 1 item (Box-folder 1/19)
          - Whatcom County, 1961; 2 items (Box-folder ½0)
      - AFL-CIO, Committee on Political Education (COPE), 1957-1961; 24 items (Box-folder ½1)
      - AFL-CIO, Committee on Political Education (COPE), Oregon, 1958; 1 item (Box-folder ½2)
      - AFL-CIO, Controller, 1958; 1 item (Box-folder ½3)
      - AFL-CIO, Department of Education, 1958-1962; 11 items (Box-folder ½4)
      - AFL-CIO, Federal Unions, 1960; 1 item (Box-folder ½5)
      - AFL-CIO, Department of Legislation, 1958-1962; 3 items (Box-folder ½6)
      - AFL-CIO, Locals, Miscellaneous, Undated; 15 items (Box-folder 1/26b)
      - AFL-CIO, Metal Trades Council, Undated; 7 items (Box-folder ½7)
      - AFL-CIO, President, 1957-1961; 8 items (Box-folder ½8)
      - AFL-CIO, Department of Publications, 1958; 1 item (Box-folder ½9)
      - AFL-CIO, Department of Public Relations, 1958; 8 items (Box-folder 1/30)
      - AFL-CIO, Radio Consultant, 1958; 4 items (Box-folder 1/31)
      - AFL-CIO, Department of Research, 1961-1962; 3 items (Box-folder 1/32)
      - AFL-CIO, Secretary-Treasurer, 1957-1960; 8 items (Box-folder 1/33)
      - AFL-CIO, Department of Social Security, 1958-1961; 4 items (Box-folder 1/34)
      - AFL-CIO, Special Representative on State Legislation, 1958; 9 items (Box-folder 1/35)
      - AFL-CIO, Union Card and Label Department, 1959-1961; 4 items (Box-folder 1/36)
      - AFL-CIO, Miscellaneous, Undated; 7 items (Box-folder 1/37)
      - American Labor Education Service, 1960; 1 item (Box-folder 1/38)
      - AFL-CIO News, 1960-1962; 3 items (Box-folder 1/39)
      - Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, International Union, United, 1957-1961; 2 items (Box-folder 1/40)
      - A Miscellaneous, Undated; 12 items (Box-folder 1/41)
      - Backstorn, Henry, 1960; 1 item (Box-folder 1/42)
      - Bakery and Confectionary Workers, International Union, American, Locals - Miscellaneous, Undated; 1 item (Box-folder 1/43)
      - Barbers, Hairdressers and Cosmetologists International Union of American, The Journeymen, Undated; 18 items (Box-folder 1/44)
      - Beckworth, Lindley, 1961; 1 item (Box-folder 1/45)
      - Bender, Jim, 1959; 1 item (Box-folder 1/46)
      - Big Brother Movement, 1957; 1 item (Box-folder 1/47)
      - Bill Posters, Billers and Distributors of the United States and Canada, International Alliance of, 1958; 1 item (Box-folder 1/48)
      - Birthright, W. C., Undated (Box-folder 1/49)
      - Blind and Deaf School Employees, Washington, 1961; 1 item (Box-folder 1/50)
      - Blough, Roger M., 1957; 1 item (Box-folder 1/51)
      - Boilmakers, Iron Shipbuilders, Blacksmiths, Forgers and Helpers, International Brotherhood of, Undated; 5 items (Box-folder 1/52)
      - Bookbinders, International Brotherhood of, Locals, Undated; 2 items (Box-folder 1/53)
      - Bricklayers, Masons and Plasterers International Union of America, Locals, Undated; 1 item (Box-folder 1/54)
      - Broadcast Employees and Technicians, National Association of, 1962; 1 item (Box-folder 1/55)
      - Brouillet, Frank B., 1961; 1 item (Box-folder 1/56)
      - Brown, Gordon J., 1959-1961; 3 items (Box-folder 1/57)
      - Building Service Employees International Union, Locals, Undated; 3 items (Box-folder 1/56)
      - Business and Industry Against Initiative 202, 1958; 5 items (Box-folder 1/59)
      - B Miscellaneous, Undated; 20 items (Box-folder 1/60)
      - California Labor League for Political Education Newsletter, 1958; 1 item (Box-folder 1/61)
      - California State Federation of Labor, 1957-1958; 3 items (Box-folder 1/62)
      - Canadian Line Congress, B.C. Federation of Labor, 1960; 1 item (Box-folder 1/63)
      - Carpenters and Joiners of America, United Brotherhood of
        - District Council, Undated; 10 items (Box-folder 1/64)
        - District Council, Locals, 25 items (Box-folder 1/65)
        - District Council, Washington State Council, 1960; 1 item (Box-folder 1/66)
      - Cement, Lime and Gypsum Workers, International Union, United, Miscellaneous, 1967; 2 items (Box-folder 1/67)
      - Central Labor Council
        - Benton-Franklin Councils, 1961; 3 items (Box-folder 1/66)
        - Everett and Snohomish Counties, 1959-1961; 2 items (Box-folder 1/69)
        - Grays Harbor, Aberdeen, 1959-1961; 2 items (Box-folder 1/70)
        - King County, 1958-1962; 13 items (Box-folder 1/71)
        - Kitsap County, 1959; 3 items (Box-folder 1/72)
        - Lewis County, 1959; 3 items (Box-folder 1/73)
        - Mason County, 1958-1959; 2 items (Box-folder 1/74)
        - Mount Vernon, 1957-1961; 5 items (Box-folder 1/75)
        - Pierce County, 1958-1961; 7 items (Box-folder 1/76)
        - Spokane, 1957-1959; 5 items (Box-folder 1/77)
        - Yakima and East Klickitat Counties, 1957-1959; 7 items (Box-folder 1/78)
        - Walla Walla, Columbia and Garfield Counties, 1959-1961; 4 items (Box-folder 1/79)
        - Wenatchee, 1961; 3 items (Box-folder 1/80)
        - Miscellaneous, Undated; 9 items (Box-folder 1/81)
      - Century 21 Exposition, Inc., 1960; 1 item (Box-folder 1/82)
      - Chemical Worker's Union, International, Undated; 10 items (Box-folder 2/1)
      - City of Hope, National Labor Council, 1959; 3 items (Box-folder 2/2)
      - Clothing Workers of America, Amalgamated, Locals, Undated; 1 item (Box-folder 2/3)
      - Cole, Bert L., 1959; 1 item (Box-folder 2/4)
      - Commercial Telegrapher's Union, The, 1961-1962; 2 items (Box-folder 2/5)
      - Committee on Political Education (COPE), Washington, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 2/5b)
      - Communications Workers of America, District 9, 1959-1961; 8 items (Box-folder 2/6)
      - Communications Workers of America. Locals, miscellaneous, Undated; 5 items (Box-folder 2/7)
      - Connor, Frank, 1960; 1 item (Box-folder 2/8)
      - Control Costa Committee on Political Education (COPE), 1957; 1 item (Box-folder 2/9)
      - Coughlin, Paul, 1957-1961; 2 items (Box-folder 2/10)
      - C Miscellaneous, Undated; 22 items (Box-folder 2/11)
      - Dade County Federation of Labor (AFL-CIO). Florida, 1962; 1 item (Box-folder 2/12)
      - Davis, Joseph H., 1957-1959; 2 items (Box-folder 2/13)
      - Davis, Ralph, 1957; 1 item (Box-folder 2/14)
      - Democratic Party, National Committee, Publicity Division, 1962; 2 items (Box-folder 2/15)
      - Democratic Party, Washington State Central Committee, 1958-1959; 7 items (Box-folder 2/16)
      - Democratic Party, miscellaneous, Undated; 7 items (Box-folder 2/17)
      - Donough, Stanley W., 1960; 1 item (Box-folder 2/18)
      - Durhan and Guimont, 1959; 2 items (Box-folder 2/19)
      - Durkhan, Martin J., 1958; 1 item (Box-folder 2/20)
      - D Miscellaneous, Undated; 6 items (Box-folder 2/21)
      - Eisen, Jack, 1958; 2 items (Box-folder 2/22)
      - Electrical Workers, International Brotherhood of, Locals, Undated; 11 items (Box-folder 2/23)
      - Engineers, International Union of Operating, Locals, Undated; 10 items (Box-folder 2/24)
      - E Miscellaneous, Undated; 6 items (Box-folder 2/25)
      - Felton, Ray, 1958; 1 item (Box-folder 2/26)
      - Fire Fighters, International Association of, Washington State Council, 1957; 1 item (Box-folder 2/27)
      - F Miscellaneous, Undated; 3 items (Box-folder 2/28)
      - Garment Workers of America, United, Locals, Undated; 3 items (Box-folder 2/29)
      - Garment Workers of America, International Ladies', Locals, Undated; 2 items (Box-folder 2/30)
      - Gillingham, J. Benton, 1958; 2 items (Box-folder 2/31)
      - Gordon, C. David, 1959; 1 item (Box-folder 2/32)
      - Government Employees, American Federation of, Locals, Undated; 3 items (Box-folder 2/33)
      - Grain Millers, American Federation of, Locals, Undated; 1 item (Box-folder 2/34)
      - Grays Harbor County, Commissioner [John Pearsall], 1959; 1 item (Box-folder 2/35)
      - G Miscellaneous, Undated; 8 items (Box-folder 2/36)
      - Hansen, Julia Butler, 1961; 2 items (Box-folder 2/37)
      - Harbor Club, Seattle, 1960; 2 items (Box-folder 2/38)
      - Heat and Frost Insulators and Asbestos Workers, Undated; 1 item (Box-folder 2/39)
      - Hod Carriers, Building and Common Laborers Union of America International, Locals, Undated; 1 item (Box-folder 2/40)
      - Holcomb, S. R., 1959; 1 item (Box-folder 2/41)
      - Holman, Carl Viking, 1958; 4 items (Box-folder 2/42)
      - Holmes, Hal, 1959; 1 item (Box-folder 2/43)
      - Hood, Jack C., 1960; 2 items (Box-folder 2/44)
      - Horan, Walt, 1957; 1 item (Box-folder 2/45)
      - Hotel and Restaurant Employees' and Bartender's International Union, 1958; 1 item (Box-folder 2/46)
      - Hotel and Restaurant Employees' and Bartender's International Union, Local Joint Executive Board, 1960; 1 item (Box-folder 2/47)
      - Hotel and Restaurant Employees' and Bartender's International Union, Local Joint Executive Board, Locals, Undated; 11 items (Box-folder 2/48)
      - Hughes, Charles H., 1958; 2 items (Box-folder 2/49)
      - Humphrey, Hubert Horatio, 1959-1960; 2 items (Box-folder 2/50)
      - H Miscellaneous, Undated; 12 items (Box-folder 2/51)
      - Idaho State AFL-CIO, miscellaneous, Undated; 2 items (Box-folder 2/52)
      - Insurance Workers International Union (AFL-CIO), Undated; 2 items (Box-folder 2/53)
      - International Association of Industrial Accident, Boards and Commissions, Undated; 8 items (Box-folder 2/54)
      - Iron Workers, International Association of Bridge and Structural, 1958; 1 item (Box-folder 2/55)
      - I Miscellaneous, Undated; 6 items (Box-folder 2/56)
      - Jackson, Henry M., 1957-1961; 4 items (Box-folder 2/57)
      - Jewish Labor Committee, 1961; 2 items (Box-folder 2/58)
      - J Miscellaneous, Undated; 4 items (Box-folder 2/59)
      - Kansas State Federation of Labor (AFL-CIO), 1957; 1 item (Box-folder 2/60)
      - Keep Washington Green, 1957-1961; 40 items (Box-folder 2/61-2/64)
      - Kennedy, Joan Fitzgerald, 1958-1959; 2 items (Box-folder 2/65)
      - King, Chet, 1958; 1 item (Box-folder 2/66)
      - King County, Juvenile Court, 1961; 4 items (Box-folder 2/67)
      - King County, Prosecuting Attorney, 1959; 1 item (Box-folder 2/68)
      - King County Medical Service Corporation, 1959-1961; 7 items (Box-folder 2/69)
      - Kittitas County, Board of City Commissioners, 1957; 1 item (Box-folder 2/70)
      - K Miscellaneous, Undated; 4 items (Box-folder 2/71)
      - Labor, 1957; 1 item (Box-folder 3/1)
      - Labor United, 1957; 1 item (Box-folder 3/2)
      - Laundry and Dry Cleaning International Union, AFL-CIO, Undated; 5 items (Box-folder 3/3)
      - League of Women Voters of Washington, 1961; 1 item (Box-folder 3/4)
      - Lockitch, Percy A., 1957; 13 items (Box-folder 3/5)
      - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1958; 1 item (Box-folder 3/6)
      - Long, William, 1959; 1 item (Box-folder 3/7)
      - Longshoremen's Association AFL-CIO, International, Locals, Undated; 5 items (Box-folder 3/8)
      - Longshoremen's Association AFL-CIO, Puget Sound Council, 1958; 1 item (Box-folder 3/9)
      - Los Angeles County, Probation Office, 1957; 1 item (Box-folder 3/10)
      - L Miscellaneous, Undated; 15 items (Box-folder 3/11)
      - Machinists and Aerospace Workers International Association of, miscellaneous
        - General miscellaneous, Undated; 3 items (Box-folder 3/12)
        - Aeronautical Industrial District #751, 1958-1961; 2 items (Box-folder 3/13)
        - Government Employees, 1959-1961; 2 items (Box-folder 3/14)
        - Locals, miscellaneous, Undated; 5 items (Box-folder 3/15)
        - The Machinist, 1959; 1 item (Box-folder 3/16)
        - Washington State Council, 1959; 1 item (Box-folder 3/17)
      - McGoran, J. E., 1958; 2 items (Box-folder 3/18)
      - Mack, Russell V., 1957; 1 item (Box-folder 3/19)
      - Magnuson, Don, 1957-1962; 25 items (Box-folder 3/20-3/21)
      - Magnuson, Don, Campaign Committee, 1962; 1 item (Box-folder 3/22)
      - Magnuson, Warren Grant, 1957-1962; 38 items (Box-folder 3/23-3/25)
      - Magnuson, Warren Grant, Silver Anniversary Dinner, 1961-1962; 8 items (Box-folder 3/26)
      - Manolides, Evans D., 1960; 1 item (Box-folder 3/27)
      - Marine Engineers' Beneficial Association, National, 1959; 1 item (Box-folder 3/28)
      - Mast, Fred B., 1958; 1 item (Box-folder 3/29)
      - Metcalf, Jack, 1961; 1 item (Box-folder 3/30)
      - Masters, Mates and Pilots, International Organization of, 1958; 1 item (Box-folder 3/31)
      - Mayes, Nora, 1960; 4 items (Box-folder 3/32)
      - Meat Cutters and Butcher Workman of North America, Amalgamated, 1961; 3 items (Box-folder 3/33)
      - Meat Cutters and Butcher Workman of North America, Locals, Undated; 3 items (Box-folder 3/34)
      - Millard, William J., Jr., 1959-1961; 4 items (Box-folder 3/35)
      - Miller, William F., 1960-1962; 2 items (Box-folder 3/36)
      - Montana State AFL-CIO, 1958-1960; 2 items (Box-folder 3/37)
      - Morse, Wayne, Special Testimonial Dinner Committee, 1961; 1 item (Box-folder 3/38)
      - Musicians, American Federation of, 1961; 1 item (Box-folder 3/39)
      - M Miscellaneous, Undated; 40 items (Box-folder 3/40)
      - National Council for Industrial Peace, 1958-1959; 3 items (Box-folder 3/41)
      - National Hells Canyon Association, 1957; 6 items (Box-folder 3/42)
      - National Institutes on Rehabilitation and Labor Health Services, 1961; 1 item (Box-folder 3/43)
      - National Institutes on Rehabilitation and Labor Health Services, Northwest Region, 1961; 8 items (Box-folder 3/44)
      - National Planning Association, 1957-1961; 24 items (Box-folder 3/45-3/46)
      - Neva, Gena G., 1958; 1 item (Box-folder 3/47)
      - New York State AFL-CIO, 1961; 1 item (Box-folder 3/48)
      - Northwest Council for Economic Education, 1958-1960; 3 items (Box-folder 3/49)
      - N Miscellaneous, Undated; 14 items (Box-folder 3/50)
      - Office Employees International Union, Locals, Undated; 3 items (Box-folder 3/51)
      - Ohio CIO Council Radio Department, 1957; 2 items (Box-folder 3/52)
      - Oregon State Industrial Accident Commission, 1961; 1 item (Box-folder 3/53)
      - Oregon State Labor Council (AFL-CIO), 1957-1961; 7 items (Box-folder 3/54)
      - O Miscellaneous, Undated; 5 items (Box-folder 3/55)
      - Painters, Decorators and Paperhangers of America, Brotherhood of, Locals, Undated; 7 items (Box-folder 4/1)
      - Painters, Decorators and Paperhangers of America, Brotherhood of, Locals, miscellaneous, Undated; 4 items (Box-folder 4/2)
      - Papermakers and Paperworkers, United, Locals, Undated; 5 items (Box-folder 4/3)
      - Peace Corps, 1961; 4 items (Box-folder 4/4)
      - Pelly, Thomas M., 1957-1959; 4 items (Box-folder 4/5)
      - Postal Clerks, United Federation of, miscellaneous, Undated; 2 items (Box-folder 4/6)
      - Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry of the United States and Canada, United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the, Undated; 2 items (Box-folder 4/7)
      - Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry, Washington State Association of the United Association, 1959-1960; 3 items (Box-folder 4/8)
      - Printing Pressmen's and Assistants' Union of North America International, Locals, Undated; 3 items (Box-folder 4/9)